folks end up kind of worrying about
which is the best agent to use. If I use
the latest GPT and if I use Opus 4.6,
they're probably going to be roughly
equivalent in terms of what they can do.
If I switch from Opus to Haiku, then I'm
going to notice differences. What I
think is more important is ergonomics.
Do they have the features that you want
that allow you to work in the way that
you want to without having to babysit
the agent? Do they support [music]
skills? Do they have the UX that you
want? Productivity is more important
than correctness.
Correctness is something you don't have
much control over. Either the model's
trained well or it's not. Um the
productivity you get from having the
features that you want and the user
experience that you want combined with
the context management, that is a much
bigger determinant of whether you're
going to get useful outcomes rather
than, you know, which model you're using
because the frontier labs are trying
very hard to keep up with each other.
And it could also
>> be around the way you as a developer ask
your questions or or provide your
requirements because the models are
going to pick up differently, the models
are going to have different activation,
ways of activating the the the the
skills using the context. And so, it may
be and this perhaps this is why there
are so many arguments as to which, you
know, who gets the most out of which
models and agents because people are
asking things in a little different way.
So, uh yeah, a lot of it could just be
you know, which agent actually works
best with the way you like to work, the
way you ask for things. Yeah, the uh and
one of the ways that agentic coding is
problematic here is because of the
non-determinism. It is a breeding ground
for superstition. From my own experience
and working with the hundreds of
developers that I have, the whole kind
of prompt engineering doesn't seem to be
that important.
Um it's more about context management
and as you say, how you communicate
requirements. The whole like how you
phrase the question or like if you give
it a persona, I don't see that making
too much of a difference even if it is
something that is quite um immediately
engaging to humans of like we like the
idea. It it's more about framing the the
context, making sure the right
information is there, that the agent has
the ability to perceive when it's doing
the wrong thing, and whether your uh
requirements are coherent or not.
>> What three tips would you give a
developer who wants to be successful
with agentic coding?
One, get stuck in, start using
something.
Two, context management, make sure you
understand it. And three, perception,
make sure that your agent can perceive
what's going on so it can fix things.
With the uh getting started, just pick a
tool. They're all much of a muchness,
they're all fairly similar. So, just get
started with one. Don't put this off
until you think it's going to be settled
science because everything is moving
faster and continuing to move forward.
With context management, it's not
obvious what's going on under the hood.
Clear your chats regularly. Make sure
that you stay on topic. Don't give the
model an excuse to be confused about
things. Don't add everything in the
kitchen sink into your agent's MD cuz
it's just going to make things worse.
On the topic of perception,
if your agent lets you down or
frustrates you by breaking things in CI,
well, it needs to be able to see what's
going on in CI. So, add an MCP server so
it can check what's going on in the
latest build. Otherwise, you can't blame
it for when it breaks things.